Leonard Ezeudu

Lynn, MA 01905

Phone: 848-468-3710 | Email: leonardezeudu@gmail.com

Website: https://leostino.github.io/professional-portfolio/ Github: https://github.com/Leostino

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/leonard-ezeudu-78652b51/

SUMMARY

A Full Stack Web Developer with good background in Computer Science. Able to develop frontend and backend applications. Equipped with skills to create products that bring joy and satisfaction to users. A lifelong learner and a firm believer that education and learning should never stop. An excellent team player with years of experience building teamwork relationship.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Javascript, JQuery, Node js, Mysql, React, MongoDB, Express, APIs, AJAX, JSON.

Applications and others: Git, Github, Cisco Networking, Software Security, Computer Science Fundamentals, Automation Systems.

PROJECTS

APERiWidget | https://leostino.github.io/aperiWidget/ | https://github.com/Leostino/aperiWidget

- A customizable widget that provides users with weather updates as they plan their commute to work.
 It also provides recent news and stock updates. Features 4 APIs Boston's trains, weather, news and stocks.
- Worked in a team of 3 to develop this application. I worked on the weather and Boston's train APIs.
- Worked with HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, JQery, AJAX, JSON, Git.

Bamazon | https://github.com/Leostino/bamazon

- Bamazon is a Node application that simulates the purchase process of a basic e-commerce transaction. Helps customers search for products, place their orders and complete transactions. It also helps store managers to keep track of products especially when they are running low in stock, they can add to inventory.
- I developed this application solely.
- This app combines Node, Mysql and Javascript to make user's experience friendly and stress-free.

Match | https://nameless-earth-15537.herokuapp.com/ | https://github.com/Leostino/FriendFinder

- Match is an Express and Node friend-finder application meant to simulate a simple dating application. This full-stack application matches users based on personality. it gets results your users' surveys, then compare their answers with those from other users and looks for a match.
- I developed this application with HTML5, Bootstrap, Javascript, Node, Express, Path, Heroku, Git.

Professional Experience

Harvard Extension School, Cambridge MA. Web Developer.

Jan 2019 - Now

Entegris, Billerica, MA. Production Tech Support.

July 2016 - Dec 2018

Tagged products with RFID tags and serial numbers for entry into the company's SAP and database. Ran various tests to ensure the highest possible product quality and adherence to the Entegris quality standard, ISO and other standards.

Coordinated production processes and performed data entry in the company's SAP. *Key Accomplishments*:

- Part of a team of 5 that drafted a whole new testing procedures that saved time and increased efficiency.
- Raised customer expectations on quality of products by keeping records of all processes and sharing these records with customers enhanced trust.

Kurrent Resources, Nigeria.

July 2011 - August 2015

IT Project Support.

Led project team for configurations and installations of biometrics access control system, IP surveillance systems, building management systems and electronic gadgets.

Communicated with product manufacturers if any issue arises on site.

Prepared project handover documents and organised training for customers on their new systems. Designed systems with various design applications like AutoCAD, Microsoft project, etc *Key Accomplishments:*

- Built a disciplined and efficient team that delivered various projects for the company, beating deadlines and setting records.
- I restructured company's network and data resources saving cost on data.

Education

Harvard Extension School, Cambridge MA.

Full Stack Web Development.

Description: A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Nnamdi Azikiwe University, Nigeria.

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science.